<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.sourceforge.tartube</id>
  
  <name>Tartube</name>
  <summary>A GUI front-end for youtube-dl, yt-dlp and other compatible video downloaders.</summary>
  
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <url type="homepage">https://tartube.sourceforge.io/</url>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.sourceforge.tartube.desktop</launchable>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>The main window</caption>
      <image>https://tartube.sourceforge.io/screenshots/screenshot.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <releases>
    <release version="2.4.038"></release>
  </releases>

  <description>
    <p>You can fetch a list of videos from your favourite channels on YouTube, Twitch, Odysee and hundreds of other sites</p>
    <p>If buffering is an issue, you can download a temporary copy of a video before automatically opening it in your favourite media player</p>
    <p>Tartube will organise your videos into convenient folders (if that&apos;s what you want)</p>
    <p>Tartube can alert you when livestreams and debut videos are starting (works on YouTube, Twitch and Odysee by default)</p>
    <p> If creators upload their videos to more than one website (YouTube and BitChute, for example), Tartube can interact with both sites without creating duplicates</p>
    <p> Certain sites operate an &quot;only one opinion allowed&quot; policy. If you think that the censors will remove a video, against the wishes of its creators and before you&apos;ve had a chance to watch it, Tartube can make an archive copy</p>
    <p> Certain sites frequently place restrictions on a video, not because it is unsuitable for some audiences, but for purely political reasons. Tartube can, in some circumstances, see videos that are region-blocked and/or age-restricted</p>
    <p> Certain sites manipulate search results, repeatedly unsubscribe people from their favourite channels and/or deliberately conceal videos that they don&apos;t like. Tartube won&apos;t do any of those things</p>
    <p> If you want to listen to your favourite discussion videos, for example while driving a car, Tartube can make an archive copy of just the audio, rather than the full video</p>
    <p> Tartube is free and open-source software</p>
  </description>
    
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://tartube.sourceforge.io/screenshots/screenshot.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
</component>
